<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Positions | Albarqouni Lab</title>
    <link>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Open Positions</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Shadi Albarqouni 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://albarqouni.github.io/images/icon_hu681563d5489cbd6b4a3381f376416aae_52869_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Open Positions</title>
      <link>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIR/01/2023: Ph.D. position in Computational Medical Imaging – Affordable Federated Learning (m/f/d)</title>
      <link>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/phd_cir.01.2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/phd_cir.01.2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We combine excellence in research, teaching, and patient care. The University Hospital Bonn (UKB) is a maximum care hospital with more than 1,300 beds. With around 38 clinics and 31 institutes as well as more than 8,000 employees (over 5,000 full-time staff), the UKB is one of the largest employers in Bonn. Every year, the UKB treats around 50,000 inpatients and around 35,000 emergencies, as well as provides over 350,000 outpatient treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following &lt;strong&gt;full-time (38.5 hrs./week) Ph.D. position&lt;/strong&gt; is available at the &lt;strong&gt;Computational Imaging Research (CIR) Lab&lt;/strong&gt;, headed by Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni, in the &lt;strong&gt;Clinic for Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology&lt;/strong&gt; of the University Hospital Bonn, University of Bonn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phd-position-in-computational-medical-imaging--affordable-federated-learning-mfd&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ph.D. position in Computational Medical Imaging – Affordable Federated Learning (m/f/d)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;starting January 2023 or as agreed upon. The position is initially limited to three years, with the possibility of extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ph.D. position will be based in the newly founded research lab for Computational Imaging Research (CIR), which aims to develop i) fully automated, highly accurate innovative computational methods that save expert labor and efforts, and mitigate the challenges in medical imaging; namely the availability of a few annotated data, low inter-/intra-observers agreement, inter-/intra-scanners variability and domain shift, ii) innovative deep Federated Learning algorithms that can fairly distill and share the knowledge among AI agents in a robust and privacy-preserved way, and iii) affordable AI algorithms suitable for low-quality data generated by low-resource settings and point-of-care devices. As AI technology becomes the de facto knowledge discovery approach in many industries including Healthcare, federated learning (FL) has emerged as a key factor to be considered for the future of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-020-00323-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;digital health&lt;/a&gt;. With FL, collaborative learning without a centralized data lake is enabled and has already been adapted to digital health applications. In this project, we aim to broaden and strengthen our knowledge in the area of &lt;strong&gt;affordable FL&lt;/strong&gt; where models are trained and deployed in low-resource settings. The Ph.D. candidate will have the chance to test the developed affordable AI algorithms in low-resource settings and closely work with our clinicians to identify the clinical use cases.  The Ph.D. candidate will be enrolled in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mnf.uni-bonn.de/promotion&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Science&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Bonn. If you have experience with computational methods in medical imaging, this is a great opportunity to be part of our team and contribute to AI in Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your responsibilities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and create a few clinical use cases for benchmarking existing state-of-the-art (SOTA) FL algorithms. This includes running baselines and pre-/post-processing pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop innovative computational algorithms for affordable, scalable, and efficient FL models via knowledge distillation, pruning, and/or quantization methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potentially, test and deploy the developed algorithms in low-resource settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish and present scientific outcomes at Intl. conferences and high-impact journals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain close collaboration with the team members and clinical partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.Sc. in Computer Science or equivalent with an interest in Medical Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong knowledge in Machine/Deep Learning with experience in annotation-efficient deep models, e.g., unsupervised and semi-/self-supervised learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python and PyTorch including fundamental software engineering principles and machine learning design patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent analytical, technical, and problem-solving skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be highly motivated and a team player with excellent communication and presentation skills, including experience in communicating across discipline boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluent command of the English language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desirable qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track record of publications at top-tier conferences and high-impact journals in the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on experience with Federated Learning frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on experience with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://monai.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MONAI framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working in a Linux environment, with experience in shell and cluster (SLURM) scripting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in spoken and written German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we offer you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A secure future:&lt;/strong&gt; remuneration according to the German salary scale TV-L (E13 - 75%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible for families:&lt;/strong&gt; flexible working time, home office, onsite nursery, and parental care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisions for later:&lt;/strong&gt; company pension scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted public transport ticket:&lt;/strong&gt; discounted ticket for public transport (VRS)
on-site health management service: Numerous health promotion offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employer benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; Discounted offers for employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subsidized continuing education and training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Bonn is committed to diversity and equal opportunity and is certified as a family-friendly university. It aims to increase the proportion of women in areas where women are under-represented and to promote their careers in particular. Therefore, we strongly encourage applications from qualified women. Applications will be handled in accordance with the State Equality Act (Landesgleichstellungsgesetz). Applications from individuals with a certified severe disability and from those of equal status are particularly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you meet the requirements and you are looking for a challenging job? Do not hesitate and send your application including a cover letter (highlighting your qualifications), a detailed CV (with links to previous projects and code), scanned academic degrees, and the contact details of two referees (preferably by e-mail in a single PDF file up to 5 MB in size) by &lt;strong&gt;15th January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;, quoting the job advertisement no. CIR/01/2023 in your email’s subject to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:shadi.albarqouni@ukbonn.de&#34;&gt;Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIR/02/2023: Postdoctoral position in Computational Medical Imaging - Robustness and Uncertainty in MRI-guided Radiotherapy (m/f/d)</title>
      <link>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/postdoc_cir.02.2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/postdoc_cir.02.2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We combine excellence in research, teaching, and patient care. The University Hospital Bonn (UKB) is a maximum care hospital with more than 1,300 beds. With around 38 clinics and 31 institutes as well as more than 8,000 employees (over 5,000 full-time staff), the UKB is one of the largest employers in Bonn. Every year, the UKB treats around 50,000 inpatients and around 35,000 emergencies, as well as provides over 350,000 outpatient treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a collaborative &lt;strong&gt;DFG-funded research project&lt;/strong&gt; between &lt;strong&gt;TU Munich (Prof. Nassir Navab)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;LMU Munich (Prof. Guillaume Landry and PD Dr. Christopher Kurz)&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;the University of Bonn (Prof. Shadi Albarqouni)&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;full-time (38.5 hrs./week)&lt;/strong&gt; Postdoctoral position is available at the &lt;strong&gt;Computational Imaging Research (CIR) Lab&lt;/strong&gt;, headed by Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni, in the &lt;strong&gt;Clinic for Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology&lt;/strong&gt; of the University Hospital Bonn, University of Bonn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;postdoctoral-position-in-computational-medical-imaging---robustness-and-uncertainty-in-mri-guided-radiotherapy-mfd&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postdoctoral position in Computational Medical Imaging - Robustness and Uncertainty in MRI-guided Radiotherapy (m/f/d)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;starting January 2023 or as agreed upon. The position is initially limited to two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Postdoc position will be based in the newly founded research lab for Computational Imaging Research (CIR), which aims to develop i) fully automated, highly accurate innovative computational methods that save expert labor and efforts, and mitigate the challenges in medical imaging; namely the availability of a few annotated data, low inter-/intra-observers agreement, inter-/intra-scanners variability and domain shift, ii) innovative deep Federated Learning algorithms that can fairly distill and share the knowledge among AI agents in a robust and privacy-preserved way, and iii) affordable AI algorithms suitable for low-quality data generated by low-resource settings and point-of-care.  The Postdoctoral researcher will investigate the robustness and uncertainty in both discriminative (Spatio-temporal image segmentation) and generative (synthetic CT generation) deep learning-based models in MR-guided radiotherapy. The project will make use of data acquired with an MR-Linac (ViewRay MRIdian) that has recently begun clinical operation at the Department of Radiation Oncology of LMU Munich. The research project will offer a broad spectrum of topics in the scope of MR-guided radiotherapy, including deep learning-based image processing, as well as dose calculation and optimization. The postdoc will have the chance to closely work with clinicians and two Ph.D. students at both TU Munich and LMU Munich. If you have experience with computational methods in medical imaging, this is a great opportunity to be part of our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your responsibilities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop innovative computational algorithms for Robustness and Uncertainty in both discriminative (Spatio-temporal image segmentation) and generative (synthetic CT generation) deep learning-based models in MR-guided radiotherapy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish and present scientific outcomes at Intl. conferences and high-impact journals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain close collaboration with the team members and clinical partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. in Computer Science, Machine Learning, or equivalent with an interest in Medical Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong knowledge in Machine/Deep Learning with experience in discriminative and generative models, robustness, and uncertainty quantification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track record of publications at top-tier conferences in the field (e.g., MICCAI, IPMI, and MIDL) and high-impact journals in the field (e.g., Nat. Mach. Intell., MedIA, and IEEE TMI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python, PyTorch, and MONAI including fundamental software engineering principles and machine learning design patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working in a Linux environment, with experience in shell and cluster (SLURM) scripting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent analytical, technical, and problem-solving skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be highly motivated and a team player with excellent communication and presentation skills, including experience in communicating across discipline boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluent command of the English language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we offer you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A secure future:&lt;/strong&gt; remuneration according to the German salary scale TV-L (E13 - 100%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible for families:&lt;/strong&gt; flexible working time, home office, onsite nursery, and parental care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisions for later:&lt;/strong&gt; company pension scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted public transport ticket:&lt;/strong&gt; discounted ticket for public transport (VRS)
on-site health management service: Numerous health promotion offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employer benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; Discounted offers for employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subsidized continuing education and training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Bonn is committed to diversity and equal opportunity and is certified as a family-friendly university. It aims to increase the proportion of women in areas where women are under-represented and to promote their careers in particular. Therefore, we strongly encourage applications from qualified women. Applications will be handled in accordance with the State Equality Act (Landesgleichstellungsgesetz). Applications from individuals with a certified severe disability and from those of equal status are particularly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you meet the requirements and you are looking for a challenging job? Do not hesitate and send your application including a cover letter (highlighting your qualifications), a detailed CV (with links to previous projects and code), scanned academic degrees, and the contact details of two referees (preferably by e-mail in a single PDF file up to 5 MB in size) by &lt;strong&gt;15th January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;, quoting the job advertisement no. CIR/02/2023 in your email’s subject to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:shadi.albarqouni@ukbonn.de&#34;&gt;Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIR/03/2023: Medical Research Assistant (m/f/d)</title>
      <link>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/mra_cir.03.2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://albarqouni.github.io/positions/mra_cir.03.2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We combine excellence in research, teaching, and patient care. The University Hospital Bonn (UKB) is a maximum care hospital with more than 1,300 beds. With around 38 clinics and 31 institutes as well as more than 8,000 employees (over 5,000 full-time staff), the UKB is one of the largest employers in Bonn. Every year, the UKB treats around 50,000 inpatients and around 35,000 emergencies, as well as provides over 350,000 outpatient treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following &lt;strong&gt;part-time (8 hrs./week)&lt;/strong&gt; Medical Research Assistant is available at the &lt;strong&gt;Computational Imaging Research (CIR) Lab&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni, in the &lt;strong&gt;Clinic for Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology&lt;/strong&gt; of the University Hospital Bonn, University of Bonn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;medical-research-assistant-mfd&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical Research Assistant (m/f/d)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;starting January 2023 or as agreed upon. The position is initially limited to two years, with the possibility of extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical research assistant position will be based in the newly founded research lab for Computational Imaging Research (CIR), which aims to develop i) fully automated, highly accurate innovative computational methods that save expert labor and efforts, and mitigate the challenges in medical imaging; namely the availability of a few annotated data, low inter-/intra-observers agreement, inter-/intra-scanners variability and domain shift, ii) innovative deep Federated Learning algorithms that can fairly distill and share the knowledge among AI agents in a robust and privacy-preserved way, and iii) affordable AI algorithms suitable for low-quality data generated by low-resource settings and point-of-care devices. The medical research assistant is the key component in developing the next generation of AI in Medicine by providing high-quality annotations for medical imaging and radiology/pathology reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your responsibilities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting the team members in the data collection process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annotating the collected imaging data for various projects using readily available tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing quality control of annotated images collected by different partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaboration with team members and clinical partners must be maintained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medical Doctorate (MD) degree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passionate about Machine/Deep Learning in Medical Imaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be highly motivated and a team player with excellent communication and presentation skills, including experience in communicating across discipline boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluent command of the English language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we offer you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A secure future:&lt;/strong&gt; remuneration according to the German salary scale TV-Ä (Ä1/Ä2 &amp;ndash; 20%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible for families:&lt;/strong&gt; flexible working time, home office, onsite nursery, and parental care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisions for later:&lt;/strong&gt; company pension scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted public transport ticket:&lt;/strong&gt; discounted ticket for public transport (VRS)
on-site health management service: Numerous health promotion offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employer benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; Discounted offers for employees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subsidized continuing education and training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Bonn is committed to diversity and equal opportunity and is certified as a family-friendly university. It aims to increase the proportion of women in areas where women are under-represented and to promote their careers in particular. Therefore, we strongly encourage applications from qualified women. Applications will be handled in accordance with the State Equality Act (Landesgleichstellungsgesetz). Applications from individuals with a certified severe disability and from those of equal status are particularly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you meet the requirements and you are looking for a challenging job? Do not hesitate and send your application including a cover letter (highlighting your qualifications), a detailed CV (with links to previous projects and code), scanned academic degrees, and the contact details of two referees (preferably by e-mail in a single PDF file up to 5 MB in size) by &lt;strong&gt;15th January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;, quoting the job advertisement no. CIR/03/2023 in your email’s subject to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:shadi.albarqouni@ukbonn.de&#34;&gt;Prof. Dr. Shadi Albarqouni&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
